<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Double of the contract betwixt the Lord Cochran, &amp;c. and the town of Pasley.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1700</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 32 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 5 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2013-12">2013-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B02751</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing D1955D</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R176422</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">53299050</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 53299050</idno>
            <idno type="VID">179819</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B02751)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 179819)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2805:2)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Double of the contract betwixt the Lord Cochran, &amp;c. and the town of Pasley.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>8 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[Scotland :</pubPlace>
                  <date>c. 1700]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Imperfect: creased, print show-through with loss of text.</note>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: National Library of Scotland.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Cochran, William, --  Lord, fl. 1700.</term>
               <term>Paisley (Scotland) --  History --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-07</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-07</date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-09</date>
            <label>Colm MacCrossan</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-09</date>
            <label>Colm MacCrossan</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="contract">
            <pb facs="tcp:179819:1"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:179819:1"/>
            <head>DOUBLE OF THE CONTRACT <hi>Betwixt the Lord</hi> Cochran, <hi>&amp;c. And the Town of</hi> Paſley.</head>
            <p>AT <hi>Paſley</hi> the third day of <hi>May</hi> the year of God one thouſand ſix hundred and fifty eight years: It is appointed, contracted, concord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, and finally agreed, betwixt the Parties following; They are to ſay; The right Noble Lord, <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Cochran</hi> of <hi>Paſley,</hi> and <hi>Dundonald,</hi> and <hi>William</hi> Maſter of <hi>Cochran</hi> his eldeſt Son lawful, both with one Conſent and Aſſent on the one part: And <hi>William Greenlies</hi> and <hi>John Park</hi> Merchants, preſent Baillies of the Burgh of <hi>Paſley, William Love</hi> Theſaurer of the ſaid Burgh and Counſellours thereof underſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcribing for themſelves, and taking the Burden upon them for the Community of the ſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley,</hi> on the other part, in Manner, Form and Effect as af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter follows, that is to ſay, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> of <hi>Paſley,</hi> with conſent of the Convent of the Abbacy thereof for the Time, having of old given and granted to the Baillies, Council, Community and In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dwellers of the ſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley,</hi> certain Freedoms, priviledges, Liberties and Immunities, with and adjoyned to the ſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley,</hi> and contained in the Charter of the Erection of the ſamen; And the ſaid Noble Lord, <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Cochran,</hi> now Lord of the Erection of <hi>Paſley,</hi> and <hi>William</hi> Mr. of <hi>Cochran</hi> his eldeſt Son lawful, being moſt careful, that not only <hi>the haill former Freedoms, Priviledges Liberties and Immunities of old,</hi> granted and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferred in favours of the ſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley be keeped and preſerved whole, firm and entire to them:</hi> But alſo being moſt willing for the better thryving and Flouriſhing of the ſaid Burgh, <hi>to Corroborat, Strengthen and Augment the ſamen</hi> in manner after-mentioned; And therefore they the ſaid <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Cochran,</hi> and <hi>William</hi> Maſter of <hi>Cochran</hi> his eldeſt Son lawful, for di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſe and ſundry Reſpects good Cauſes and Conſiderations moving them here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>unto, and for certain Sums of Money payed, and delivered to them by the ſaids preſent Baillies and Council of the ſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley,</hi> and their ſaid Theſaurer wherewith the ſaid <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Cochran,</hi> and <hi>William</hi> Maſter of <hi>Cochran</hi> his Son grants them ſatisfied, diſcharging them thereof for ever; Have renounced, dimitted and over-given, and hereby renounce, dimit and overgive frae them, the ſaid <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Cochran,</hi> and <hi>William</hi> Maſter of <hi>Cochran</hi> his Son, their Heirs Succeſſors and Aſſigneys, all Right of the Superiority of the ſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley</hi> within the Bounds thereof after-ment<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned,
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:179819:2"/> to the effect and intent the foreſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley,</hi> Freedoms, Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berties and Priviledges of the ſamen, in all time coming may be holden of his Highneſs, the Lord Protector of the Common-wealth of <hi>England, Scotland</hi> and <hi>Ireland,,</hi> and Dominions thereunto belonging, and his Highneſs Succeſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſors Superiors thereof; Likeas the ſaid <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Cochran,</hi> and <hi>Willi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam</hi> Maſter of <hi>Cochran</hi> his Son lawful, both with one Conſent and Aſſent as ſaid is, be the Tenor hereof, Renounce, Quite-claim, Diſcharge, Diſpone &amp; Over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>give frae them and their foreſaids, to and in favours of the ſaids Baillies, Council, Community, Theſaurer and Inhabitants of the ſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley,</hi> and their Succeſſors, all Right of Property and Magiſtracy of the ſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley,</hi> and Election of the Baillies, Council, Clerk, Burgeſſes, Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers and other Members thereof, in all time coming, and of the Tenements, Lands and others, within the ſame Burgh and Lands of <hi>Seedhill</hi> annexed thereto, within the Bounds after-mentioned, and Territory of the ſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men (except the Millns called the <hi>Seedhill</hi> Millns, Corn, Kilns there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of, Milln-Hills, or Shilling-Hills of the ſamen, and Thirled and Aſtricted Moultures of the ſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley,</hi> and Knaveſhip thereof according to uſe and wont, and of the Lands after-mentioned within the Territory there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of, to the effect they the ſaids Baillies, Council and Community of the ſaid Burgh, and their Succeſſors, may bruik, enjoy and poſſeſs the ſamen, conform to their reſpective Titles thereof, and may be in Capacity and pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er to Elect, Choiſe, Change and continue their own Magiſtrats, Baillies, Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cil, Theſaurer, Clerk, Burgeſſes, Officers and all other Members neceſſary and uſual within the ſaid Burgh, as they ſhall think convenient: And in like manner they the ſaid <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Cochran,</hi> and <hi>William</hi> Maſter of <hi>Cochran</hi> his Son, both with ane Conſent and Aſſent as ſaid is, for them and their foreſaids, hereby ſell, diſpone, renounce, aſſign and overgive frae them and their foreſaids, to and in favours of the ſaids Baillies, Council, Theſaurer &amp; Community of the ſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley,</hi> and their Succeſſors for the publick uſe of the ſaid Burgh, all and ſundry the Feu-duties of old addebted, obliſht and uſual to be payed to the Abbot and Convent of the ſaid ſometime Ab<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bacie of <hi>Paſley,</hi> and ſenſyne to the Lords of the Erection of <hi>Paſley,</hi> and their Factors and Chamberlains furth of and for the ſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley,</hi> Houſes, Biggings, Yards, Tenements, Aikers, Teinds and parcels of Land thereof weſtward frae the eaſt-end of the Bridge of <hi>Paſley,</hi> and Muſtard yard dyke, including and comprehending the Lands of <hi>Calſiſyde, Orchard, Bladoyard, Snaddon, Huthead, Hillhead, Welmeadow, Broomlands</hi> and others within the Bounds, Territory and Limits of the ſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley,</hi> Property and Commontie of the ſamen (excluding the Feu-duties of the Lands called <hi>Oxſhaw-wood</hi> and <hi>Wardmeadow,</hi> whilk are no ways comprehended in this preſent Diſpoſition and Aſſignation above-written: To the Effect and In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent, that the ſaids Baillies, Council, Theſaurer and Community of the ſaid Burgh and their Succeſſors, may hereby have full Right and power as by the Tenor hereof, the ſaid <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Cochran,</hi> and <hi>William</hi> Maſter of <hi>Cochran</hi> his Son for them and their foreſaids, now Give, Grant and Commit to them the ſaids Baillies, Council, Theſaurer and Community of the ſaid Burgh, and their Succeſſors, their full Right and power to collect, gather, uplift and receive, all and ſundry the ſaids Feu-duties of the ſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley,</hi> Houſes, Biggings, Yards, Tenements, Aikers, Roods and parcels of Lands thereof, within the Bounds above-mentioned, Including and Comprehend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing as is above included and comprehended, and excepting and ſecluding, as is a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bove
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:179819:2"/> excepted and ſecluded of the Cropt &amp; year of God one thouſand ſix hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred fifty eight years inſtant; Both <hi>Whitſunday</hi> and <hi>Martinmas</hi> Terms of the ſame, and yearly and termly in all time coming. And to imploy and be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtow the ſamen to the publick and common uſe and good of the ſaid Burgh, Emolument and Profit thereof, and giff need beis to call, follow and purſue therefore, Decreets, Sentences, Precepts and Executorials thereupon, to ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain, raiſe, uſe and cauſe put to Execution, and to give Diſcharges thereof, and to do every other thing needful thereanent, as the ſaid <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Cochran</hi> or either of them, or their foreſaids might have done, giff they had not made thir preſents: And moreover the ſaid <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Cochran,</hi> and <hi>William</hi> Maſter of <hi>Cochran</hi> his Son, both with one Conſent and Aſſent, for them and their foreſaids, <hi>Hereby ratifie and approve</hi> to them, the ſaids Baillies, Theſaurer, Council and Community of the ſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley,</hi> and their Succeſſors for ever, their former and accuſtomed Priviledges and Liberties of that part of the Moſs of <hi>Paſley,</hi> which is bounded betwixt the Marches of <hi>Ferguſlie</hi> and <hi>Merksworth,</hi> conform to their former Right and Title thereof and Poſſeſſion uſed and wont; And by thir preſents, they the ſaid <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Coch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ran,</hi> and <hi>William</hi> Maſter of <hi>Cochran</hi> his Son, both with one Conſent and Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent for them and their foreſaids, <hi>Renounce, Diſpone and overgive</hi> frae them and their foreſaids, in favours of the ſaids Baillies, Theſaurer, Council and Community of the ſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley,</hi> and their Succeſſors, <hi>all Right, Title, and Intereſt,</hi> whilk they the ſaids <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Cochran, William</hi> Maſter of <hi>Cochran</hi> his Son, or either of them, or their foreſaids, <hi>had, have, or can pretend</hi> to that part foreſaid, of the ſaid Moſs of <hi>Paſley,</hi> betwixt the ſaid Matches of <hi>Ferguſlie</hi> and <hi>Merksworth, made or to be made,</hi> to the effect that the ſaids Bail<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lies, Theſaurer, Council and Community, and their Succeſſors may bruik, enjoy, and poſſeſs the ſamen in all time-coming, conform to their ſaid Rights thereof Title and Poſſeſſion uſed and wont; <hi>And</hi> of the whilk Right of Superiority above-written of the ſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley,</hi> within the Bounds above ſpecified, including and comprehending, as is above included and comprehended, and excepting and ſecluding as is above-excepted and ſecluded; The ſaid <hi>Willi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>am</hi> Lord <hi>Cochran,</hi> and <hi>WIlliam</hi> Maſter of <hi>Cochran</hi> his Son, bind and oblige them and their foreſaids, to formally and legally diveſt themſelves in the Hands of His ſaid Highneſs the Lord Protector of the Common-Wealth of <hi>England, Scotland</hi> and <hi>Ireland,</hi> and Dominions thereunto belonging, and his Succeſſors, or their Commiſſioners of Exchequer in this Nation, <hi>ad perpetuam remanentiam,</hi> to the effect the ſaid Superiority may con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>form to the Laws and Statutes of this Nation, be conſolidat in the per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon and favours of His ſaid Higneſs, and his Succeſſors for ever. <hi>And</hi> ſick<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>like, the ſaid <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Cochran,</hi> and <hi>William</hi> Maſter of <hi>Cochran</hi> his Son, hereby bind and oblige them, and ilk one of them, conjunctly and ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verally, and their foreſaids, by all legal and lawful means, to diveſt and de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nude themſelves, and their foreſaids of the ſaid Property of the ſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley,</hi> and Magiſtracy thereof, and Election of the ſaids Baillies, Clerk, Bur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>geſſes, Officers, and all other Members thereof, <hi>and of all Right</hi> that they or their foreſaids can or may in time-coming claim or pretend thereto, and to the Tenements, <hi>Lands and others foreſaids,</hi> within the ſaid Burgh, including and comprehending as is above included and comprehended, and excepting and ſecluding as is above excepted and ſecluded, to the effect and intent above<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpecified, and to the ſaids Feu-duties of old addedbted and due to the ſaid Abbot
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:179819:3"/> and Convent of the ſaid ſometime Abbacey of <hi>Paſley,</hi> and ſenſyne to the ſaids Lords of Erection of <hi>Paſley,</hi> and payable to them furth of the ſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley,</hi> Houſes, Biggins, Yards, Tenements, Aikers, and parcels of Lands thereof within the Territory of the ſamine, and Bounds above-mentioned, including and comprehending as is above included and comprehended, and excepting and ſecluding as is above excepted and ſecluded, to the effect and in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent above exprimed, and <hi>of all Right Title or Intereſt</hi> foreſaid, whilk the ſaid <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Cochran, William</hi> Maſter of <hi>Cochran</hi> his Son, and their foreſaids <hi>had, have, or can pretend to</hi> that part foreſaid of the Moſs of <hi>Paſley,</hi> bewixt the Marches foreſaid of <hi>Ferguſly</hi> &amp; <hi>Merksworth,</hi> made or to be made, in manner above-ſpecified, to the effect and intent above contained, by reſignation of the ſamine in the hands of his ſaid Higneſs the Lord protector of the Common-wealth of <hi>England, Scotland</hi> &amp; <hi>Ireland,</hi> &amp; Dominions thereunto belonging, or his high<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs Succeſſors, Superiors thereof, or their ſaid Commiſſioners of Exchequer, in fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vours of the ſaid Baillies, Council, &amp; Community of the ſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley</hi> and their Succeſſors, and for new Infeftment to be made, given and granted to them thereof, to be holden by them, from the ſaid <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Cochran, Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam</hi> Maſter of <hi>Cochran</hi> his Son, and their foreſaids, Of the ſaid Lord Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tector, and his Highneſs Succeſſors, in all time coming, in free Blench, for payment of an <hi>Scots</hi> penny yearly at the feaſt of <hi>Whitſunday,</hi> at the Mercat-Croſs of the ſaid Burgh, in name of Blench Ferm, giff it beis asked, allener<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, and ſicklike, for payment yearly to his ſaid Highneſs, and his Succeſſours of the Sum of Seven pounds good and uſual <hi>Scots</hi> Money, as an proporti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>onal part of the Blench-duty of the ſaid erected Lordſhip of <hi>Paſley,</hi> for the ſaid <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Cochran,</hi> his ſaid Son, and their foreſaids, their Relief of the ſaid Blench-duty of the ſaid Erected Lordſhip of <hi>Paſley, pro tante,</hi> Or by payment thereof, to the ſaid <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Cochran, William</hi> Maſter of <hi>Cochran</hi> his Son, and their foreſaids, to be imployed, and applyed by them, for their own Relief of the ſamen, at the Option of the ſaids Baillies and Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cil of <hi>Paſley,</hi> and their Theſaurer and Succeſſors. And with ſpecial Clauſe of Warrandice, of the Infeftment foreſaid. Likeas now, as give the ſamen Infeftment were made and perfected, and then as now. The ſaid <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Cochran,</hi> and <hi>William</hi> Maſter of <hi>Cochran</hi> his Son, hereby bind and ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lige them, conjunctly and ſeverally, and their foreſaids, to Warrand, Acquite, and defend to the ſaids Baillies and Council, and Community of the Burgh of <hi>Paſley,</hi> and their Succeſſors and Theſaurer, the Premiſſes above diſpon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, Aſſigned and Ratified to them, als freely and quietly, in, and be all things, as is above-mentioned, from them the ſaid <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Cochran,</hi> and <hi>William</hi> Maſter of <hi>Cochran</hi> his Son, and their foreſaids, their own proper Facts and Deeds allenarly. That is to ſay, that they, nor any of them, nor their foreſaids have not done, nor ſhall not do any Fact or Deed, in hurt and prejudice of the Premiſſes, in any ſort. <hi>And moreover the ſaid Willi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam</hi> Lord <hi>Cochran,</hi> and <hi>William</hi> Maſter of <hi>Cochran</hi> his Son, hereby alſo bind and oblige them, and ilk ane of them, and their foreſaids, that they or any of them in the purchaſe of their new Signature and Infeftment of the ſaid erected Lordſhip of <hi>Paſley,</hi> ſhall either cauſe to be <hi>Excepted, Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerved</hi> and expunged the haill Priviledges, Liberties and Feu-duties, and o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers above-diſponed above aſſigned, and above-ratified by them to the ſaids Baillies, Council, and Community of the ſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley,</hi> and their Succeſſors, give they the ſaid Baillies, and Council of <hi>Paſley,</hi> and their Suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſors,
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:179819:3"/> ſhall find the ſame Conducing, for their Security: Or other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wayes, <hi>the Inſerting,</hi> and not excepting, reſerving and expunging thereof furth of the ſaid Signature and Infeftment, ſhall no wayes derogat any thing from this abovewritten Security, nor extenaut, nor weaken the ſame, but to the contrair, ſhall be in <hi>Fortification and Corroboration</hi> hereof. And ſhall be an <hi>Supervenient Right</hi> to them, The ſaids Baillies, Council and Community of the ſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley,</hi> and their Succeſſors, for that effect. And the ſaid <hi>Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam</hi> Lord <hi>Cochran,</hi> his ſaid Son, and their foreſaids, are, and ſhall be fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther bound and oblidged hereby, for the further Strengthening and Securing of the Premiſſes to the ſaids Baillies, Council and community of the ſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley,</hi> and their Succeſſours, in all time coming, That the ſaids <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Cochran</hi> his Son, nor their foreſaids, <hi>ſhall not purchaſe, in hurt or prejudice of this abovewritten Security, Any new Gifts or Donation</hi> of the Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſes Above-aſſigned, Diſponed and Ratified. But to the contrair, ſhall not only abſtain therefrae, Or giff any ſuch Gift or Donation ſhall be ſo pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chaſed by them, or to their behoof, The ſame ſhall <hi>Acreſce,</hi> and be alſo Supervenient to the ſaids Baillies, Council and Community of the ſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley,</hi> and their Succeſſors? &amp; ſhal be Transferred in their favours, in ſo far as may ſecure the Premiſſes to them. And it is provided, and declared hereby, That this preſent abovewritten Security of the Feu-duties foreſaids, made and granted by the ſaids <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Cochran,</hi> and his ſaid Son, to the ſaids Baillies, Council and Community of the ſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley,</hi> and the Succeſſors, ſhall be upon, and with ſpecial Condition, That notwithſtanding of the Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſes, the ſamen Feu-duties ſhall be Redeemable, to his Highneſs, the Lord Protector, ſuperiour foreſaid, and his Succeſſors, or to the Heretors of the ſaids Lands, Tenements and others foreſaids, out of which the ſamen are pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able, conform to the Act of Parliament, Laws and Conſtitutions of this Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion. And yet thereby the ſaid yearly Duty of ſeven pounds money foreſaid, ſhall no ways be impaired nor diminiſhed: And for the making and perfecting to the ſaids Baillies, &amp; Council and Community of the ſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley,</hi> and their Succeſſors, of the ſaid Infeftment &amp; Reſignation abovementioned the ſaids <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Cochran,</hi> and <hi>William</hi> Maiſter of <hi>Cochran</hi> his Son, both with one conſent and aſſent, have made conſtitute and ordained, and by the tenor here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of Make, Conſtitute and Ordain their Lovits and ilk ane of them conjunctly and ſeverally, there very lawful, undoubted and irrevocable Procurators, Actors, Factors, and ſpecial Errand-bearers, to the effect After-ſpecified, Givand, Grantand and Committand to them, and like<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ane of them, as ſaid is, Their very full, free and plain power general and ſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cial, expreſs bidding, mandament and Charge. To compear before his ſaid Highneſs, the Lord Protector of the Common-wealth of <hi>England, Scotland</hi> and <hi>Ireland,</hi> and Dominions thereunto belonging, and his Highneſs Succeſſors, Superiors foreſaids, or before his Highneſs Commiſſioners of Exchequer of this Nation: And there, for, and in Name of the ſaids, <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Cochran,</hi> and <hi>William</hi> Maſter of <hi>Cochran</hi> his Son, and upon their behalfe, to Renunce, Reſigne, freely quite clame, Diſcharge, Surrender over and up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>give purely and ſimply be Staff and Baſton, as uſe is. As they now by the tenor hereof, Renunce, Reſign, Freely Quite Claime Diſcharge, Surrender over and up-give frae them, and their foreſaids, the foreſaid Superiority, or Right of ſuperiority abovewritten, of the ſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley,</hi> within the bounds above-ſpecified, Including, and Comprehending, as is above Includ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:179819:4"/> and Comprehended. And Excluding, as is above Excluded, with all Right, Title, and Intereſt, whilk they, or their foreſaids had, have, or can pretend thereto, in the hands of his ſaid Highneſs, or his Succeſſors, Su<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>periors foreſaid, or their Commiſſioners foreſaids, in their Names, <hi>ad per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>petuam remanentiam,</hi> in manner after-ſpecified, and to the effect above-men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned: And alſo, for them, the ſaid <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Cochran,</hi> and <hi>William</hi> Maſter of <hi>Cochran</hi> his Son, and in their Names, and upon their behalfs, to Renunce, Reſign, freely Quite-clame, Diſcharge, Surrender, Over and Up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>give, frae them, and their foreſaids, purely and ſimply, by Staff and Baſtoun, as uſe is, as they now hereby Renounce, Reſign, freely Quite-clame, Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charge, Surrender, Over and Up-give from them and their foreſaids, in the hands of the ſaid Superior, or Commiſſioners of Exchequer foreſaid, the ſaid Property of the ſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley,</hi> and Magiſtracy thereof, and Election of the ſaids Baillies, Council, Clerk, Burgeſſes, Officers, and other Members thereof, and of the ſaids Tenements, Lands, and others within the ſamen Burgh, and Lands of <hi>Seedhill</hi> foreſaid, annexed there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to, within the Bounds above and after-mentioned, and Territory of the ſame, except the ſaids Milns, called the Seedhill Milns, Corn Kilns thereof, Miln<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hills, or Shilling Hills of the ſamen, and Thirled and Aſtricted Multures of the ſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley,</hi> and Knaveſhips thereof foreſaid, according to Uſe and Wont. <hi>And of the Lands above and after-mentioned within the Terri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>torie thereof,</hi> to the Effect and Intent above-ſpecified, and all and ſundry the ſaids Feu-duties above-mentioned, of old addebted and due to the ſaid Abbot, and Convent of the ſaid ſometime Abbacy of <hi>Paſley,</hi> &amp; ſenſyne to the ſaids Lords of the Erection of <hi>Paſley,</hi> forth of the ſaids Houſes, Biggings, Yards, Tenements of the Burgh of <hi>Paſley,</hi> Aikers, Rudes, and parcels of Land thereof Weſtward, frae the ſaid Eaſt-end of the ſaid Bridge of <hi>Paſley</hi> and Muſtard-yard-dyke, inclu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding and comprehending the ſaids Lands of <hi>Calſiſyde, Orchard, Bladoyard, Snaddoun, Hut-head, Hill-head, Well-meadow, Broom-lands,</hi> and others within the bounds above-written, and limits of the ſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley Property and Commonty of the ſamine,</hi> (excluding the Feu-duties of the ſaid Lands of <hi>Ox<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhaw-wood</hi> and <hi>Ward-meadow,</hi> which are no ways comprehended within this preſent Reſignation) to the effect and intent above exprimed. And ſick<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>like, all <hi>Right, Title,</hi> and <hi>Interest</hi> foreſaid, whilk the ſaid <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Coch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ran,</hi> and William Maſter of <hi>Cochran</hi> his Son, or any of them, or their foreſaids had, have, or can pretend to that part foreſaid, of the ſaid Moſs of <hi>Paſley,</hi> betwixt the ſaid Marches of <hi>Ferguſly</hi> and <hi>Merksworth,</hi> made or to be made, to the effect above-contained; and that the ſaids Baillies, Council and Commu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nity of the ſaid Burgh, and their Succeſſors, may brook, enjoy, and poſſeſs the ſamine in all time coming, comform to their ſaid Right thereof, Title and Poſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſſion uſed and wont, in the ſpecial favours of the ſaids Baillies, Council and Community of the ſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley</hi> and their Succeſſors, and for new In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feftment to be given to them thereof, to be holden in manner above mentio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned, and thereupon Inſtruments and Documents to take, ask, lift and raiſe; and generally all and ſundry other things, to do, uſe and exerce in the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſes that to the Office of Procuratory, in ſuch caſes of the Law, and conſue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tude of this Nation is known to appertain, or that the ſaid <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Coch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ran,</hi> and <hi>William</hi> Maſter of <hi>Cochran</hi> his Son, or any of them might do them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves if they were perſonally preſent, firm and ſtable, holding and for to hold all and whatſomever other things by their ſaids Procurators, or any of them, in the premiſſes, in their Names, righteouſly appertains to be done, and thereat obliges them to abide, without Appellation or Reclamation. FOR THE
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:179819:4"/> WHILKS CAUSES, the ſaids Baillies and Council of the ſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley,</hi> and their ſaid Theſaurer for themſelves, and in name of the Community of the ſaid Burgh, hereby bind and oblidge them and their Succeſſors, Baillies, Council and Community and Theſaurer of the ſaid Burgh, either in manner foreſaid to make Payment yearly to his ſaid Highneſs the Lord Protector of the Common-wealth foreſaid, and his Succeſſors, and Commiſſioners of Exche<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quer, of the ſaid Sum of ſeven Pounds Money of <hi>Scotland</hi> yearly, as a pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portional part of the ſaid Blench Duty of the foreſaid erected Lordſhip of <hi>Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſley,</hi> for the ſaid <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Cochrane,</hi> his ſaid Son and their foreſaids their re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lief of the ſaid Blench Duty of the ſaid erected Lordſhip of <hi>Paſley pro tanto;</hi> and for that effect to procure and deliver to them yearly Accquittances &amp; Diſcharges thereof, beginning the firſt years relief thereof for this Inſtant year of God one thouſand ſix hundred &amp; fifty eight years, &amp; ſua forth in all time coming, or elſe to make Payment to the ſaid <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Cochrane</hi> his ſaid Son and his foreſaids, of the ſaid yearly Duty of Seven Pounds Money foreſaid, to be imployed or applyed by them for their own relief of the ſamine, beginning the firſt years payment as is above written, &amp; that at the option of the ſaids Baillies, Council, Theſaurer, and Community of the ſaid Burgh, and their Succeſſors; and ſua forth to continue in all time coming as they ſhall choiſe, in manner foreſaid yearly. And becauſe the ſaid <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Cochrane,</hi> and <hi>William</hi> Maſter of <hi>Cochran</hi> his Son, have in manner as is above-mentioned, conferred on the ſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley</hi> divers Favours, Courteſies and Reſpects, therefore the ſaids Baillies, Theſaurer, and Council of the ſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley,</hi> hereby binds and oblidges them and their Succeſſors in Office, that not only they and their ſaids Succeſſors ſhall themſelves in all time coming endeavour to live peaceably, and to give to the ſaid <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Cochrane,</hi> and <hi>William</hi> Maſter of <hi>Cochran</hi> his Son, and to their Families and Succeſſors at all occaſions, all due Honour, Reſpect and Obſervance becoming them, and to do their beſt en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deavours to counſel the Inhabitants of the ſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley</hi> to do in like man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner the ſamine, but alſo that they the Magiſtrats of the ſaid Burgh ſhall yearly in all time coming, immediatly after their Election go to the Place of <hi>Paſley,</hi> if the ſaid <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Cochran, William</hi> Maſter of <hi>Cochran</hi> his Son, or their Succeſſors and their Families be there abiding, or reſiding for the time, or how ſoon thereafter they ſhal come there to abide; and there ſhal ſolemnly declare and demonſtrate to them the ſaid <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Cochran,</hi> his ſaid Son, and there Succeſſors foreſaids, their humble acknowledgment of the favours, Courteſies and Reſpects foreſaids, conferred by them on the ſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley,</hi> and give unto them the ſaids <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Cochran,</hi> his ſaid Son, and their foreſaids therefore, all Honour, Obſervance and Reſpect due to them, with all condign Reverence. And it is provided and declared hereby, that this preſent Security above-written, and Warrandice therein contained, ſhall not be extended to the propriety of that Tenement within the ſaid Burgh of <hi>Paſley</hi> diſponed by the ſaid <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Cochran</hi> to <hi>John Snodgraſs</hi> Burgeſs there which formerly pertained to <hi>Andrew Sempill</hi> of <hi>Bruntfields,</hi> nor to the Propriety of the Land without the Weſt Port of <hi>Paſley,</hi> which ſometime pertained to Umquhile <hi>John Stwart</hi> called of <hi>Bridgend,</hi> or <hi>Margaret Cochrane</hi> his Spouſe, nor to the Propriety of that piece of Land extending to an half Rude of Land, or thereby, near the <hi>Gateſ-law,</hi> called <hi>Cocksmailling;</hi> But that the Propriety of the ſaid Particulars ſhall be excepted forth of the Secu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity and Warrandice foreſaid; and the exception of the Propriety thereof
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:179819:5"/> foreſaid, ſhal no ways prejudge the ſaids Baillies, Council, and Community of the ſaid Burgh, and their Succeſſors, and their Theſaurer, of the Feu-du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties of the Premiſſes ſua above excepted; but the Feu-duties thereof accuſtom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed ſhall hereby belong to the ſaids Baillies, Council and Community, and their Succeſſors and Theſaurers in all time comming, and the ſame ſhall be holden of the ſaids Baillies and Council, and their Succeſſors, as the reſt of the Tenements and Lands within the ſaid Burgh reſpectively, are and ſhall be holden for ever. And for the mair ſecurity, both the ſaids Parties are content and conſents that thir preſents be Inſert and Regiſtrat in the Court Books of Juſtice, or court Books of any other Judicatory in this Nation, there to remain for the future memory of the Premiſſes, and to have the ſtrength of a Decreet of the Judges thereof, and their Authorities to be interponed there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to, that Letters of Horning on ſix days Charge, Poynding and others may paſs hereupon as effeirs. And hereunto they conſtitute their Lovits.</p>
            <p>And ilk one of them conjunctly and ſeverally their Procurators, in moſt ample form of Procuratory. In Witneſs whereof thir preſents are Written by <hi>Robert A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lexander</hi> of <hi>Black-houſe,</hi> Writer in <hi>Paſley,</hi> whereof the other double is Writ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ten by Mr. <hi>Robert Wallace</hi> his Servant. Both the ſaids Parties have Subſcribed the ſamine with their Hands, Day, Month, Year and Place foreſaid, before thir Witneſſes, Collonel <hi>Allexander</hi> and <hi>Gawin Cochrans,</hi> Brethren German to the ſaid <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Cochran, James Dunlop</hi> of <hi>Houſe-hill, James Freeland</hi> Fiar of that Ilk, Servant to the ſaid <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Cochran,</hi> and the ſaid Mr. <hi>Robert Wallace</hi> Writter, and <hi>John Mackerrell</hi> Brother to <hi>Hill-houſe. Sic Subſcri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bitur Cochrane.</hi> W. <hi>Cochran, John Perk</hi> Baillie, <hi>John Spreul. John Kelſo, John Corſwell, Iohn Wallace, William Greenlees; William Adam, William Love</hi> Theſaurer, <hi>William Henderſon, Iohn Wilſon, Robert Parkhil, Andrew Wilſon, Thomas Iuctice Robert Alexander</hi> Nottar Publick do Subſcribe thir preſents, for, and at command of the ſaid <hi>William Greenlees,</hi> one of the Baillies of the ſaid Burgh, and of <hi>Iohn Snodgraſs, Patrick Baird, William</hi> and <hi>Iohn Paterſon,</hi> Counſellers of the ſaid Burgh, becauſe they cannot Write themſelves, as they aſſert, Witneſſing my Sign and Subſcription, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> I <hi>Robert Perk</hi> Notar Publick required in the Premiſſes, have Subſcribed the ſame at command above-writ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ten, theſe my Hand-writ and Sign teſtifying, <hi>&amp;c. A. Cochran</hi> Witneſs, <hi>Ga: Cochran</hi> Witneſs, <hi>Ia. Dunlop</hi> Witneſs, <hi>Ia. Freland</hi> Witneſs, <hi>Iohn Mackerrel</hi> Wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs, <hi>Ro. Wallace</hi> Witneſs, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <pb facs="tcp:179819:5"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
